pgs-soft.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy policy

### Privacy Policy

Is your personal information important to you? We know it is. It’s important to us too. That’s why we respect your privacy and make sure that your personal data is only used by us with your consent.

We want to assure you that our Website, i.e. [ www.pgs-soft.com](https://www.pgs-soft.com/) , does not automatically collect any information about you, except for information contained in cookies. Your e-mail address is only associated with a cookie when you fill in a form on our Website. Based on this, our marketing-automation system gains an insight into your browsing behaviour on our Website, dating back to before you filled in the form. 

We will write a little more about cookies in another part of the Privacy Policy.

The Privacy Policy we have prepared aims to inform you about WHERE, WHEN, AND WHY we collect your personal data. It also specifies which type of data we process. In it, you will find information about what you can require from us and about your rights

#### Let’s get started

GDPR – such a fashionable abbreviation nowadays. But what does it mean? It’s short for **The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** (EU) 2016/679. It’s a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union. It also addresses the export of personal data outside the EU. The GDPR aims primarily to give control to citizens and residents over their personal data and to simplify the regulatory environment for international business by unifying the regulation within the EU.

**When will GDPR be in effect?** GDPR was adopted on 14 April 2016, and, after a two-year transition period, becomes enforceable on 25 May 2018.

**What is considered personal data?** Any information regarding an identified or identifiable natural person is considered to be personal data. Personal data will be, for example, your name, surname, e-mail address, telephone number, the name of your Company, your job title, or your computer’s IP address. 

**The Personal Data Controller** or **ADO** is ourselves: PGS Software S.A. Our headquarters is located at 3 Sucha Street in Wroclaw, Poland. 

In this Privacy Policy, when we use the term **Website** , we are referring to a website, which we manage, i.e. [ www.pgs-soft.com](https://www.pgs-soft.com/).

#### Where do you get my data from?

We receive your data directly from you when you fill in a contact form on our Website, or when you send us a question.

#### What kind of data do you process?

We follow the principle of minimisation, i.e., we only process the data which is necessary for us to achieve the purpose of processing, i.e., your name, surname, e-mail address, and optionally, your telephone number.

#### What is the purpose and legal basis for the processing of your personal data by us?

We also process your personal data for the purposes set out below, (based on PGS Software’s legitimate business interests), which are 

  * replying to a question / message you have sent;
  * conducting statistical analyses.

If you give YOUR consent, we process your personal information in order to 

  * contact you, including for purposes related to authorised marketing activities, through available communication channels, in particular, by e-mail and telephone
  * send you commercial information via electronic means of communication

You can withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data at any time, in the same way as you expressed it. We will process your personal information until you withdraw your consent.

#### Do you have to provide us with your personal details?

No, of course not. As we already mentioned, browsing our Website does not mean you must provide your personal data; however, if you do not enter your data, we will not be able to deal with your query.

#### Do we transfer your data to countries outside the European Economic Area?

Your personal data will be transferred outside the European Economic Area, i.e. to technological platforms used for data integration and analysis as well as marketing and advertising activities; however, these platforms guarantee a high level of personal data protection. These providers are able to guarantee the highest level of data security because they are obliged to use standard contractual clauses adopted by the Commission (EC) or to participate in the Privacy-Shield programme established by the Commission for Implementing Decisions (EU) 2016/1250 of 12 July 2016 on the adequacy of protection provided by the EU-US Privacy Shield.

#### Do we process your personal data automatically (including through profiling) in a way that affects your rights?

Your personal data will be processed in an automated way (including in the form of profiling); however, it will not result in any legal consequences for you or substantially affect your situation..

Profiling means the processing of personal data by means of using your personal data to evaluate some of your features. This data includes the country and city from which you are visiting our Website, your IP address, browser, and the operating system of the device from which you visit our Website.

However, we wish to assure you that we do not make automated decisions in relation to you or your personal data. We only practise profiling in order to better match the content we show you and to create profiles for the Website’s users. 

#### What are your rights concerning PGS Software S.A in terms of the processing of your personal data? 

We want you to know that you are entitled to

  * access your data and to receive copies of said data. You have the right to obtain confirmation from us as to whether we are processing your personal data, and, if this is the case, you have the right to 
    * gain access to your personal data,
    * obtain information about the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data being processed, the recipients or categories of recipients of this data, the planned period of storage of your data or criteria used for determining this period, about your rights under the GDPR, and the right to lodge a complaint against the supervisory body, about the source of said data, about automated decision-making, including profiling, and the safeguards applied in connection with the transfer of this data outside the European Union,
    * obtain a copy of your personal data.
  * to **rectify (correct) the data**. You have the right to request that we correct your personal data (if it is incorrect) and supplement it (if it is incomplete) 
  * to **delete the data** (the right to be forgotten) - if in your opinion there is no reason for us to process your data, you can request that we remove it. You have the right to request the deletion of your personal data if: 
    * you withdraw your consent to the extent to which personal data was being processed based on your original consent 
    * your personal data has ceased to be necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or processed
    * you object to the use of your data for marketing purposes
    * you object to the use of your data for Website statistics and for user satisfaction analysis – and your opposition is justified
    * your personal data has been processed unlawfully.

Despite your request to delete your personal data, in connection with your opposition or withdrawal of consent, we may retain certain details of your personal data, which would be necessary to establish, assert, or defend claims. This applies in particular to personal data including your name, surname, e-mail address, and claims related to the use of our services.

  * **data processing limitations** \- you may request that we limit the processing of your personal data only to store or perform the actions agreed on with you, if in your opinion we are in possession of incorrect data about you, or process it unjustifiably, or you do not want us to remove it because you need it to assert, determine, or defend claims, or you need it during the time of your opposition to the data processing. You have the right to request restrictions on the use of your personal data in the following cases: 
    * when you question the correctness of your personal data – in such a case, we will limit its use for the time needed to verify the accuracy of your data
    * if the processing of your data is against the law, and, instead of removing the data, you demand restrictions on its use
    * where your personal information has ceased to be necessary for the purposes for which we have collected or used it, but it is necessary for you to determine, assert, or defend claims
    * if you object to the use of your data – in such a case, the restriction occurs for the time needed to consider whether, (due to your individual situation), the protection of your interests, rights, and freedoms outweighs our interest in processing your personal data.
  * to **object to the processing of your data** for the purposes of conducting direct marketing. If you exercise this right, we will stop processing your data for this purpose. If your objection turns out to be well founded, and we have no other legal basis to process your personal data, we will delete your personal information.
  * to **transfer data** \- you have the right to receive from us – in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, e.g. CSV, – the personal information you provided to us based on your consent. You may also ask us to send this data directly to another entity
  * to **lodge a complaint against the supervisory body**. You can lodge complaints, ask questions, and make requests regarding the processing of your personal data and the right to exercise your rights. If you feel that we are processing your data unlawfully, you can file a complaint to the supervisory body, i.e. The Bureau of the Inspector General for the Protection of Personal Data located at 2 Stawki Street in Warsaw, Poland.

#### With whom do we share your personal information? 

We can disclose your data only if you give your consent for us to do so, or, if necessary, to authorised entities. Additionally, those of our employees who must have access to your data in order to perform their daily professional duties will have access to your data. Our subcontractors, i.e., entities we use to process your data, will also have access to your data. The said subcontractors are technology platforms used for integrating and analysing data, and conducting marketing and advertising activities.

#### For how long do we store your data?

The personal data we process, such as your name and e-mail address, telephone number, company name, and job title, will be kept until you object to it being processed. If you’d like us to delete your data, you should withdraw your consent. Otherwise, we might decide to terminate the processing of your data if we determine that the consent received from you has become obsolete.

#### How can you contact us?

If you’d like to contact us, you can do so by filling in the contact form on our Website, or by writing to us at [gdpr@pgs-soft.com](mailto:gdpr@pgs-soft.com)

### Cookies Policy

  * The Website does not automatically collect any information about you, except for information contained in cookies.
  * Cookie files ("cookies") are IT data units, in particular, text files which are stored on the Website’s end user’s device, and are intended to be used on the Website’s pages. Cookies usually contain the name of the website from which they originate, their storage time on the end user’s device, and a unique number.
  * The entity which places cookies on the end user's device and gains access to them is PGS Software S.A.
  * Based on cookies, our marketing automation system observes your behaviour on the Website, such as, for example, which of the Website’s pages you visited, how long the visit lasted, what kind of content you downloaded, and which forms you filled in. 
  * Until you enter your e-mail address, your activities on the Website are recorded anonymously, (we do not know who you are, but we know, for example, which country you are from, which type of browser you use, and which type of device you use to browse the Website). 
  * Cookies are used to adjust the content of the Website’s pages to the end-user's preferences, and to optimise the use of the Website; in particular, these files allow us to recognise the Website user's device, which consequently allows us to properly display the Website in a manner tailored to the end-user’s individual needs. They also allow us to create statistics, which help us understand how end users browse the Website, which allows us to improve its structure and content.
  * The Website may use two basic types of cookies: "session" and "persistent" cookies. Session cookies are temporary files, which are stored on the user's end device until they log out, leave the Website, or turn off the software (web browser). Persistent cookies are stored in the user's end device for the time specified in the cookie-file parameters or until they are removed by the user.
  * The following types of cookies may be used as part of the Website 
    * "necessary" cookies, which facilitate the use of services available on the Website, e.g. authentication cookies used for services which require authentication on the Website
    * cookies used to ensure security, e.g. used to detect fraud in the field of authentication on the Website
    * "performance" cookies, which enable the collection of information regarding the use of the Website’s pages 
    * "functional" cookies, which allow settings selected by the end-user to be “remembered” and for the end-user’s interface to be personalised, e.g. the end-user’s selected language, region, font size, website appearance, etc. 
    * In many cases, software used for browsing websites (web browser) allows cookies to be stored in the end-user's device by default. Website users may change their cookie settings at any time. These settings can be changed in the web browser’s settings in such a way as to block the automatic handling of cookies, or to inform the end users about each time the cookies are being activated on the Website user’s device. Detailed information regarding how cookies can be handled is available in the software (web browser) settings. 
    * The Website operator states that restrictions on the use of cookies can affect some of the functionalities available on the Website.
    * Cookies placed on the Website user's device may also be used by advertisers and partners cooperating with the Website operator.
    * More information about cookies can be found in the "Settings" or "Help" section of your browser's menu.

### Trademarks & Copyrights

    * Unless otherwise stated, the copyrights to pages, information, materials, and their deployment within the Website, belong to PGS Software S.A., or have been transferred with the appropriate licence to PGS Software S.A. 
    * The Website also contains trademarks, trade names, and logos reserved both by PGS Software S.A., and by companies and third parties. The trademarks, trade names, and logos have been used only to identify them. By making the trademarks, trade names, and logos available on the Website, PGS Software S.A. does not grant a licence to use them in any way. 
    * Users may print, duplicate, copy, or temporarily store, parts of the Website for their own purposes, or in connection with the use of PGS Software S.A. products and services.
    * Users are not allowed to make any changes to the Website’s content. 
    * The detailed scope of the permitted and unlawful use of Website content is regulated by law, in particular, the Act of 4 February 1994 on copyright and related rights (Journal of Laws of 1994, No. 24, item 83, as amended) . Violation of these rights can result in civil and/or criminal sanctions.
